In this lesson, we'll be talking about creating a process to source clients.
سوف نتحدث في هذا الدرس عن عملية البحث عن مصدر للعملاء.
Now let's take a look at what that really means.
ولنلق الآن نظرة على ما يعنيه ذلك.
Now, as we discussed in the last lesson,
كما ذكرنا في الدرس السابق
there are primarily two parties in a freelancing ecosystem.
فإن هناك طرفان في نظام العمل الحر.
One is the freelancer,
الأول هو الموظف الحر
which is you, and the other is the client.
الذي هو أنت، والثاني هو العميل.
Now there are lots of clients out there who are looking
هناك الكثير من العملاء الباحثين
for freelancers like you to get their task done.
عن أشخاص مثلك لإنجاز مهامهم.
But the question is,
ولكن السؤال الآن هو
how to find those clients and how can they find you?
كيف تعثر على أولئك العملاء وكيف لهم أن يعثروا عليك؟
That is what we will cover in this lesson.
وهذا هو ما سنتناوله في هذا الدرس.
Apart from that, we will also talk about strategies of how to win a client.
وبالإضافة إلى ذلك، سنتحدث عن استراتيجيات كسب العميل.
Meaning, how can you apply to work on
بمعنى كيف لك أن تتقدم للعمل على
the freelancing project to increase your chances of actually getting that project.
مشروع حر وتزيد من فرصك لكسب المشروع بالفعل.
Now that we've gone through the introduction of the course,
الآن بعد أن انتهينا من مقدمة الدورة التدريبية،
let's start with the very first step in
لنبدأ بالخطوة الأولى في
our freelancing journey of finding clients to work for.
رحلة عملنا الحر، وهي إيجاد عملاء للعمل لحسابهم.
But before that, let's take a look at what we'll cover in this lesson at a high level.
لكن قبل ذلك، دعونا نلقي نظرة على ما سنقوم بتغطيته في هذا الدرس على مستوى أعلى.
First, we'll start with setting a mindset to adopt when starting a freelancing career,
سوف نبدأ أولاً بتحديد طريقة التفكير التي يجب أن نتبناها عند البدء في امتهان العمل الحر
which would make it quite helpful to go through
والتي سوف تسهل علينا المضي
the rest of the lesson and this entire course.
في بقية الدرس وفي الدورة بأكملها.
Next, we will discuss the different channels available out there to source clients,
بعد هذا سوف نناقش القنوات المختلفة المتاحة لإيجاد العملاء،
where to find clients that you can work with.
أي كيف تجد العملاء الذين يمكنك العمل معهم.
Then we'll dive a little bit deeper,
وبعد هذا سوف نتعمق أكثر
specifically into freelancing platforms,
في منصات العمل الحر تحديدًا
which are a great way to find clients when you are starting a freelancing career.
والتي تعتبر طرقًا ممتازة لإيجاد العملاء وأنت في بداية مشوارك المهني الحر.
Starting with the introduction,
بعد هذه المقدمة
we'll discuss profile creation and platform walkthrough.
سوف نتناول إنشاء الملف الشخصي وتعريف بالمنصة.
Next, we'll discuss sending what we call
بعد ذلك، سوف نناقش إرسال ما نطلق عليه
an expression of interest to work on a client request on these platforms.
"رسالة إبداء الاهتمام" بالعمل على طلبات العملاء على تلك المنصات.
Not only that, we'll discuss strategies to send a winning expression of
وليس هذا فحسب، سنناقش أيضًا استراتيجيات إرسال رسالة إبداء اهتمام ناجحة
interest to increase your chances of getting the task to work on.
لزيادة فرصك في قبولك للعمل على المهمة.
Lastly, we'll quickly summarize what we went through in the lesson.
وأخيرًا، سوف نقوم سريعًا بتلخيص ما تناولناه في الدرس.
Let's take a look now at what we will be able to do by the end of this lesson.
الآن، لنلق نظرة على ما سوف نتمكن من فعله بانتهاء هذا الدرس.
First, we'll be able to utilize freelancing platforms to find new clients.
أولًا، سوف نصبح قادرين على استخدام منصات العمل الحر لإيجاد عملاء جدد.
Second, we'll be able to create a profile on a freelancing platform.
وثانيًا، سوف يكون بإمكاننا إنشاء الملف الشخصي على منصة من منصات العمل الحر.
Then as discussed earlier,
وبعد هذا وكما ذكرنا سابقًا،
we'll be able to send an expression of interest
سوف يكون بإمكاننا إرسال رسائل إبداء الاهتمام
to apply to work on a client request by adopting
للتقدم للعمل على طلبات العملاء
strategies discussed in this lesson that could
الاستراتيجيات الموضحة في هذا الدرس والتي بإمكانها
increase our chances of getting the project to work on.
أن تزيد من فرصنا لكسب المشاريع للعمل عليها.